Guide to the Bedford-Stuyvesant Community Cooperative Audio Tapes, 1966-1967. RL.10040
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bedford-Stuyvesant Community Cooperative audio tapes
1966-1967
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bedford-Stuyvesant Community Cooperative
RL.10040
1.5 Linear Feet Five boxes, including three boxes containing 33 audio tapes, and two boxes containing preservation master and use copies on 124 compact discs.
Thirty-three 1/4-inch open-reel audio tapes recording meetings of various directors and committee members of the Bedford-Stuyvesant Community Cooperative, especially the founders, Gerald Schaflander and Henry Etzkowitz. Issues discussed include disagreements, employment and firings, stealing, finances, violence and gang fights, drugs, students, the FBI, and black and white division of labor. Notes on some of the boxes include names of persons involved, events, quotes, and content.
Collection Overview
Thirty-three 1/4-inch open-reel audio tapes recording meetings of various directors and committee members of the Bedford-Stuyvesant Community Cooperative, especially the founders, Gerald Schaflander and Henry Etzkowitz. Issues discussed include disagreements, employment and firings, stealing, finances, violence and gang fights, drugs, students, the FBI, and black and white division of labor. Notes on some of the boxes include names of persons involved, events, quotes, and content.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Digital listening copies are available for all tapes. Original audiovisual materials are closed for playback use, although the tape boxes, some of which contain extensive notes, may be viewed. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Historical note
The Bedford-Stuyvesant Community Cooperative was a racially-integrated organization founded by sociologists Gerald Schaflander and Henry Etzkowitz in 1966, as a way to connect the diverse residents of Brooklyn's Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood to goods and services, including food, medicine, and childcare, while investing profits back into the community.
Audiovisual materials; New York (State); Sound recordings; Cooperative societies -- New York (State); Minorities -- Employment -- New York (State); New York (State) -- Race relations.; Etzkowitz, Henry; Bedford-Stuyvesant Community Cooperative; Schaflander, Gerald M.
- Open reel audio tapes, 1966-1967; 1
  - Dec 9, car to Boston A, 1966 December 9; 1
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_01)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-001)
  - Dec 9, car to Boston B, 1966 December 9; 2
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_02)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-001)
  - Dec 9, car to Boston C, 1966 December 9; 3
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_03)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-002)
  - Dec 9, car to Boston D, 1966 December 9; 4
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_04)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-002)
  - 12/9 1 + 2, 12/9 3 + 4, 1966 December 9; 5
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_05)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-003)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-004)
  - 12/9 5 + 6, 12/12 1 + 2, 1966 December 9, 12; 6
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_06)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-005)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-006)
  - 12/27 1A + 1B + 2, 1966 December 27; 7
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_07)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-007)
  - 12/28 1A + 1B, 12/28 2A + 2B, 1966 December 28; 8
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_08)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-008)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-009)
  - 12/28 Pt. 3 + 4A, 12/28 4b, 12/29 1A, 1966 December 28; 9
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_09)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-010)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-011)
  - 12/29 1b + 2A, 12/29 2B + 3A, 1966 December 29; 10
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_10)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-012)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-013)
  - 12/29 3b + 4A, 12/29 4b + 5, 1966 December 29; 11
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_11)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-014)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-015)
  - 12/29 6A + 6b, 12/29 7A + 7b, 1966 December 29; 12
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_12)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-016)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-017)
  - January 12, Tape 1a, 1967 January 12; 13
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_13)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-018)
  - Jan 12, Part 1b, 1967 January 12; 14
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 1, Audio-reel OR_14)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-018)
  - Jan 12, Part 2a, 1967 January 12; 15
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_15)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-019)
  - Jan 12, Part 2b, 1967 January 12; 16
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_16)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-019)
  - Jan 12, Part 3a, 1967 January 12; 17
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_17)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-020)
  - Jan 12, Part 3b, 1967 January 12; 18
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_18)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-020)
  - Jan 12, Part 4a, 1967 January 12; 19
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_19)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-021)
  - Jan 12, Part 4b, 1967 January 12; 20
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_20)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-021)
  - Jan 13, GS + HE, 1967 January 13; 21
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_21)
    - Compact disc use copy (Box 5, Cd UC-022)
  - Jan 25 + Jan 28, 1967 January 25, 28; 22
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_22)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-023)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-024)
    - Compact disc use copy, 3 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-025)
    - Compact disc use copy, 4 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-026)
    - Compact disc use copy, 5 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-027)
    - Compact disc use copy, 6 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-028)
  - February 2, 1967 February 2; 23
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_23)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-029)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-030)
    - Compact disc use copy, 3 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-031)
    - Compact disc use copy, 4 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-032)
    - Compact disc use copy, 5 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-033)
    - Compact disc use copy, 6 of 6 (Box 5, Cd UC-034)
  - February 16, 1967 February 16; 24
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_24)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-035)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-036)
    - Compact disc use copy, 3 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-037)
    - Compact disc use copy, 4 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-038)
    - Compact disc use copy, 5 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-039)
  - March 7, H.E. + J.B.; Butch Eccleston + GS, 1967 March 7; 25
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_25)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-040)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-041)
  - 3/14 1 + 2 + 3A, 3/14 3b + 3c, 1967 March 14; 26
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_26)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-042)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-043)
  - March 18, 1967 March 18; 27
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_27)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-044)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-045)
  - March 18, 1967 March 18; 28
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 2, Audio-reel OR_28)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-046)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-047)
  - 3/25 + 3/2, 1967 March 2, 25; 29
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 3, Audio-reel OR_29)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 3 (Box 5, Cd UC-048)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 3 (Box 5, Cd UC-049)
    - Compact disc use copy, 3 of 3 (Box 5, Cd UC-050)
  - March 22, GS-Cliffe E., G.S., Elliot Jeffries, 1967 March 22; 30
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 3, Audio-reel OR_30)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-051)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-052)
    - Compact disc use copy, 3 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-053)
    - Compact disc use copy, 4 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-054)
    - Compact disc use copy, 5 of 5 (Box 5, Cd UC-055)
  - March 29, 1967 March 29; 31
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 3, Audio-reel OR_31)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-056)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-057)
  - Trip to D.C., 1A-1B-2A, 2b + 3, undated; 32
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 3, Audio-reel OR_32)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 3 (Box 5, Cd UC-058)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 3 (Box 5, Cd UC-059)
    - Compact disc use copy, 3 of 3 (Box 5, Cd UC-060)
  - G.S. + students, undated; 33
    - Original 1/4-inch open reel audio tape (Box 3, Audio-reel OR_33)
    - Compact disc use copy, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-061)
    - Compact disc use copy, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Cd UC-062)